We haven't talked about investing for a long time, so let's chat with everyone today.
Many friends who are familiar with me know that I am a long-term investor in Tesla, and I have been holding it since the end of 2018.
this is the most successful investment of my life.
Therefore, many old viewers have asked me, why don't you try to find the next Tesla?
For example,  people often ask me, why don't you invest in NVIDIA?
Seeing the recent crazy rise of companies like AMD and Oracle,
including Lemonade, which a good friend of mine invested in, is also growing like crazy.
Many people will be curious, why would you miss these obvious investment opportunities,
and not invest in these hot stocks?
So, today I want to use this video to briefly share why I don't try to find the next Tesla,
or why I don't pursue investing in those so-called hot stocks.
I will mainly talk about four reasons, and among them, I will also recommend a book to everyone.
But before we start,
I want to take thirty seconds to thank the channel's long-term partner, Interactive Brokers. IB is
an award-winning and widely recognized global broker, and it is also my platform for investing in US stocks.
I like it for two main reasons. First, its transaction costs are very low.
In many regions, there are no handling fees or the fees are so low that they have no impact.
Second, its currency exchange costs are very competitive.
I often have to convert Canadian dollars to US dollars when buying US stocks in Canada.
Compared to Canadian brokers that charge a handling fee of more than 1.5%, IB's exchange rate is simply
too low, and that alone is enough for me to choose them.
IB has many other advantages, far beyond what I have mentioned, such as paying interest on cash in eligible accounts.
Its options trading function is also very powerful and inexpensive.
I strongly recommend that you click the link in the comment section to check out Interactive Brokers.
Clicking the link will benefit me, so it's a way of supporting me.
Okay, let's get started.
I don't look for the next Tesla because doing so is meaningless in most cases.
It's a kind of half-measure.
Those who often watch my videos know that I am a die-hard fan of the American drama,  Breaking Bad. You can tell from my T-shirt.
There is an episode in Breaking Bad that left a particularly deep impression on me.
It's called "No half measure."
This line comes from the character Mike in the show, and it means,  either don't do it, or do it all the way.
This has always been one of my life mottos.
In fact, this is even more true in investing.
in portfolio management, there are basically two major schools of thought.
the first is the complete diversification school.
I have always recommended that ordinary people invest in S&P 500 index funds. this is an extremely diversified strategy.
You can even configure a global index, own stocks of all companies, own everything.
The second extreme is,  the complete concentration school,
which is to highly concentrate your investment portfolio in a very small number of stocks, or even just one or two.
These two schools of thought actually correspond to two seemingly contradictory sayings in the investment world. One is,
don't put all your eggs in one basket, and the other is,
put all your eggs in one basket, and then carry that basket well.
The former talks about diversification, while the latter talks about concentration.
So which one is right?
I think both are right. They correspond to the optimal solutions under different conditions and goals.
Let's talk about concentrated investing first. If you want to,  make big money in the stock market, you usually need two conditions:
enough principal, and an investment target that can multiply many times, for example, a ten-bagger stock.
To achieve this, you must put all your eggs in one basket, which is an extremely risky behavior.
Most people actually don't have the objective conditions to do so, because most people,
actually can't afford to lose.
There are only two situations where you can bear this kind of risk. Either you bet your entire life savings,
win and change your life, lose and be doomed forever; or your assets are already so large
that you can take out a very considerable amount of principal for concentrated investment, and even if this investment fails,
your overall financial safety margin will remain stable.
Obviously, very few people can meet these conditions.
Now let's look at diversified investing. This path seems ordinary,
but for most people, it is a wise strategic choice.
Because the real purpose of diversified investing is not just to diversify risks, but to concentrate attention.
When you choose to buy the S&P 500 index, you are actually making a decision.
I give up my ambition to pursue excess returns in the stock market in exchange for my most precious resources, time and energy.
Then you can take the time and energy you saved, just like concentrating your investment in one stock,
and invest it all in places that are more important to your life, to improve your ability to make money outside of the market,
and develop your career.
This is also a form of concentrated investment, except that your investment target is yourself.
So,  concentrated investment and diversified investment,  their strategies do not conflict. If you want to get high returns,
you are destined to concentrate your investment on one target.
Some people meet the conditions for concentrated investment in the stock market, while others meet the conditions for concentrated investment in personal development.
You always need to concentrate your resources in one place and disperse the remaining resources in another.
This actually reminds me of Buffett's example. Everyone knows that Buffett, recommends that ordinary people invest in the S&P 500.
But if you look closely, he is more of a concentrated investor.
Most of his capital is placed in a very small number of companies. Is this Buffett,  being hypocritical,
and deceiving us ordinary people?
Not at all. His so-called hypocrisy is precisely his understanding that different people are suitable for different investment strategies.
It's just like how he responded to a little girl's question at a shareholder meeting a few years ago.
The little girl asked him, "It seems like there are no investment opportunities left." He said, "The best thing you can invest in,
is actually yourself." This applies to the little girl, and it also applies to most of us.
What does this have to do with me not looking for the next Tesla?
My investment portfolio has long been Tesla plus the S&P 500. Tesla has already achieved my concentrated investment layout.
I don't go all-in because I want to protect my own margin of safety.
So I diversify the rest of my safety margin funds into the S&P 500, so as not to distract my attention,
so that I can focus on my career. I will talk more about this later.
For me, looking for the next Tesla is actually taking the middle road,
which is a half measure.
For example, today I invested in,  NVIDIA, tomorrow I invested in AMD,  and then the day after tomorrow I bought Oracle.
This seems to have diversified the risk, but in fact my investment portfolio is neither concentrated enough,
nor truly diversified.
For example, if I have a million, and I divide it among seven or eight stocks, how should I allocate it?
Most likely, I will put the vast majority of my funds in Tesla, which I understand best and have the most confidence in, while the positions of other stocks,
will be very small. In this way, even if I am lucky enough to buy a ten-bagger stock, because the principal is too low,
it will be insignificant to my overall return.
More importantly, a person's energy is limited.
To be honest, just researching Tesla alone has already taken up a lot of my energy.
in the past, from Elon Musk's interviews, speeches, and related books,
to the company's various AI Days, and doing various research, the time consumed is huge.
At least at this stage, I don't have the energy to study another company in depth.
Let me give you an example of my own. I once bought some Google stock.
After ChatGPT came out, I started to feel that Google had a big company disease.
In the AI era, it might be difficult to turn around. I sold it when I had a slight profit.
But now that I'm studying AI, I find that my initial judgment of Google on the AI track was inaccurate.
So you see, my so-called long-term investment in Google was held for a very short time.
The fundamental reason is that I didn't understand this company enough, or my conviction was not deep enough, so I couldn't hold on to it at all.
Of course, this doesn't mean you can only go all-in on one stock.
If you have enough energy to have a deep understanding and conviction in every company in your portfolio, you can of course manage a,
concentrated portfolio of multiple stocks.
But what you will face is,  not only divided energy,
but also the constant dilemma of how to allocate funds among them.
To me, this is also doing things halfway, and this half measure will lead to new problems.
This is the next reason why I don't try to find a second Tesla.
(Sound effect)
Chasing hot stocks can easily lead to some bad habits,
because it will push you into the role of a short-term trader and a gambler.
This is because when you start asking, "Why didn't I buy that soaring stock?"
your decision-making starting point has already been hijacked by the stock price performance.
You start to pay attention to it not because of your conviction after long-term research, but because it has risen.
This in itself is a very dangerous signal.
There's a saying I particularly like, I forgot the original words, but it roughly means,  if you are shocked by the world,
then maybe there is a problem with your cognitive model of the world.
If you are a true long-term investor and have conviction in a company,
you should discover its value when its stock price is low or has been performing poorly for a long time,
not just passively notice it when it soars.
Being surprised by the surge in stock prices just shows that you haven't done enough homework.
When you buy because you are chasing the rise, you actually have no conviction in this company, so once it starts to fall,
you will easily think, ah, maybe I was wrong, maybe this is just a bubble, and then sell it quickly.
This kind of,  chasing highs and selling lows behavior will make you further and further away from true long-term investing.
There is a popular joke on the internet that compares short-term trading with long-term holding.  the general idea is that,
a person sells a stock every time it rises by 20%. For example, they buy at 20 and sell at 24, buy at 40,
and sell at 48, making a total of 12.
But if he had held on from 20 and sold at 48, he would have made 28,
which is much higher than that 12.
Compared to long-term investing, short-term trading is more like,  picking up sesame seeds and losing the watermelon.
Of course, this is a very simplified example, and it ignores complex fluctuations such as declines.
I recognize that short-term trading has its value, but what I want to emphasize is that it is a completely different game.
You need to think clearly about what your original intention is.
If you want to get a tenfold return and find the next Tesla,
you will most likely need to hold for the long term.
But the mentality of chasing hotspots will make you FOMO and lose your balance.
When you catch a soaring stock, you will regret not betting high enough at the time, and your principal is not enough.
So what to do?
Many people will choose to add leverage, using margin or options.
At this time, investing gradually approaches gambling.
So, I am not willing to look for those so-called next ten-bagger stocks. I don't want them to disrupt my position,
and turn me into a trader or a gambler.
My original intention of investing in Tesla was to hold it for the long term.
In the past, it was my ten-bagger stock, and I believe it will continue to be in the future.
We will talk more about this at the end.
There is a saying in English that I particularly like: "What got you here, won't
get you there."
The old path that brought you to today will not take you to a new distant place.
I heard this sentence a long time ago, but a book I've been reading recently
has given me a deeper understanding of it in terms of personal finance and investment.
This book is called "The Wealth Ladder."
I've read "Just Keep Buying" by the same author before.
And the book we read together in our book club in September is his new book this year.
In the past few years, my channel has often talked about the topic of financial freedom, but in fact,
financial freedom is a very subjective and vague concept. It is related to your income, expenses,
lifestyle, and psychological state.
And this book, "The Wealth Ladder," directly discards this definition,
and instead divides wealth into six objective ladders.
The core idea of this book is that the method you use to get from the first ladder to the second ladder
may not necessarily help you get from the second ladder to the third ladder.
If you want to cross different ladders, you need to use different methods.
For example, I used to say that you should be frugal. When you are initially accumulating capital,
this is a crucial virtue.
But when you are already a multi-millionaire, although frugality is still important,
you can't become a billionaire just by saving money. You need to introduce new methods.
This is why we cannot blindly imitate the practices of successful people.
I have previously criticized the kind of investment-linked insurance sold to ordinary people. Many people who refuted me
would give examples of how much insurance Li Ka-shing bought.
But Li Ka-shing is Li Ka-shing, and we are not.
We are at completely different stages of life and capital. He has a family office that we don't have.
The problems he needs to consider are completely different from ours. Even all our assets are not comparable to the money he pays his lawyers.
And you simply can't buy the same insurance that Li Ka-shing buys.
Using his methods to guide our lives is no different from carving a mark on a moving boat to find a sword.
These are mostly just sales pitches from insurance salespeople.
You must see clearly which stage you are at.
So for me, this investment in Tesla has to a large extent,
helped me complete a very important leap on the wealth ladder.
But if I want to go up another level,
it is very likely that stock investment alone will no longer be able to take me further.
I shared a statistic in a previous video.
The truly,  level five and six wealthy people,
their stock market asset allocation may only account for about 30% of their total assets. This is not intentional on their part,
to only put in so little.
The real reason is that the value of their businesses and careers outside the stock market is too high,
so high that their stock market assets seem small. That is to say,
what helps them achieve,  the leap across the wealth ladder is their own career.
This reminds me of a conversation I had many years ago with my friend's father,  who is a successful entrepreneur,
a billionaire.
At that time, I asked him, "I have a sum of money. Should I buy a house first,
or invest it in my own business first?" He asked, "
what is the return on your business?" I said, "Roughly estimated,
it's about 1000%." Then he said without hesitation, "Then what are you waiting for?
Of course you should invest it in your business."
Looking back at this conversation now, two points have left a deep impression on me. First, I overestimated myself at the time.
My business could not be scaled simply by investing money, so,  I ended up buying a house.
However, that experience did teach me a lot of lessons that I can use in my current startup.
The second interesting point is that when I said a tenfold return,
that entrepreneur uncle was not surprised at all.
It was only after many years of starting a business that I understood that for business people, achieving a tenfold,
or even a hundredfold return is possible and happens from time to time. This is a very important way for individuals to break through the wealth ladder.
Of course, there is a high risk of failure. Being able to reach level five or six
is a rare achievement in itself, which speaks for itself.
But if you want to cross this ladder, investing in your own company,
the aspects you can manipulate and control are far more than looking for a needle in a haystack in the stock market.
I have shared this in detail in a previous video, so I won't go into it again.
So you see, the strategy is phased. In the early stages of the wealth ladder,
you should focus your energy on your ability to make money outside of the market and invest in yourself.
In the middle stage, you may indeed need to rely on stock investment.
And interestingly,  for my current stage, if I want to go up further,
the next ten-bagger stock I need to invest in may not be another company, but my own business.
You see, this brings us back to the starting point of investing in yourself.
So, I highly recommend everyone to read this book.
The last reason is actually very simple. I believe that Tesla itself still has huge potential.
There is no need for me to look for a second Tesla.
After it has risen so much, I am not only continuing to hold it, but I am even constantly buying more.
The last time I bought was,  after I went to Austin to participate in the Robotaxi,  the first trial operation.
I believe that Tesla's second wave of growth, a story about physical world AI,
is just beginning now.
From FSD V12 to V13, to the introduction of the just-released V14,
and the rapid development of Optimus in a few years and the third-generation robot waiting in the wings,
we can already get a glimpse of the future.
When autonomous taxis and general-purpose humanoid robots become popular, the changes they bring to the world will be disruptive.
Perhaps the growth trend of Tesla as an electric vehicle company has slowed down, but as an artificial intelligence and robotics company,
a,  physical world AI company, the grand trend of autonomous taxis, Optimus, and energy,
is only just beginning.
I think this story is much bigger than the story of electric cars.
I will have the opportunity to talk more about these with you later.
So, I don't need to look for the next Tesla.
It is enough to hold on to the basket in my hand and do a good job in the next stage of my life.
OK, that's all for today's sharing.  thank you for watching, and I hope it can inspire you.
See you next time, bye!
[speaker_1] (Outro music)